RG 089:001, State Highway Department
Connecticut State Library
State Highway Department records
1894-1993
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. State Highway Dept
53 cubic feet
In 1895, the General Assembly established a three person board known as the State Highway Commission to monitor town expenditures of state funds as well as construction and improvements to public roads. In 1897, the legislature abolished the board and created the State Highway Department headed by the State Highway Commissioner. In October 1969, it merged into the new Department of Transportation.
RG089_001
Multiple
Historical Note
In 1895, the General Assembly established a three person board known as the State Highway Commission to monitor town expenditures of state funds as well as construction and improvements to public roads. In 1897, the legislature abolished the board and created the State Highway Department headed by the State Highway Commissioner. In October 1969. it merged into the new Department of Transportation.
See also the.
Scope and Content
Included here are road improvement registers, 1894-1913; papers from the Supervisor of Repairs, 1921-1929; manuals and organizational studies, 1930-1987; Hartford Bridge Commission, 1939-1951; Groton-New London Bridge Commission, 1939-1943; Old Lyme-Old Saybrook Bridge Commission, 1945-1951; reports and studies, 1939-1992; news clippings and maps, circa 1940-1965; photographs, circa 1930-1958; certificates of finished projects, 1895-1931; report on the Merritt Parkway, 1937; report on the West Rock Tunnel, 1948-1949; George S. Koch papers, 1975; photographs and blueprints of the Merritt Parkway toll plazas, 1939-1988; surveyor field books, 1956-1962; papers of the personnel administrator, 1942-1969; engineers' files including those of Warren M. Creamer, 1933-1984, and Harry Mardoian, 1917-1960; blueprints, 1922-1960; a manual from the Bureau of Fiscal Services, 1968; and Route Change Notices from the Bureau of Planning & Design, 1957-1993.
Related Material
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
RG 089:011, Aerial photographs, see the Research Guide to Aerial Photographs at the Connecticut State Library
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Groton-New London Bridge Commission; Connecticut. Hartford Bridge Commission; Connecticut. Old Lyme-Old Saybrook Bridge Commission; Connecticut. State Highway Dept
Subjects:
Transportation -- Connecticut; Bridges -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Bridges -- Connecticut -- Groton; Bridges -- Connecticut -- New London; Bridges -- Connecticut -- Old Lyme; Bridges -- Connecticut -- Old Saybrook; Raymond E. Baldwin Bridge (Old Lyme and Old Saybrook, Conn.); Charter Oak Bridge (Hartford and East Hartford, Conn.); Thames River Bridge (Groton, Conn. and New London, Conn.); Connecticut Turnpike (Conn.); Merritt Parkway (Conn.); Roads -- Connecticut -- Design and construction; Roads -- Connecticut -- Maintenance and repair
Document Types:
Blueprints; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Manuals (instructional materials); Minute books; Reports; Photographs
Restrictions on Access
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Accession 2013-032 was transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 30, 2013.
Container List
- Series 1. Road improvement registers, 1894-1913; 1977-007
  Arranged by year, then by county, then by town.
  - 1896-1896 (Volume Item 1)
  - 1895-1913 (Volume Item 1a)
- Series 2. Supervisor of Repairs, West Willington, 1921-1929; 1978-016
  - Papers, 1921-1929; 1 envelope (24 items) (Box Item 2)
    Routine notification of responsibility assignments for road, bridge and fence maintenance.
- Series 3. Manuals and organizational studies, 1930-1987
  - T002753
    - Report of the organization and procedures of the State Highway Department, 1930 November; Griffenhagen and Associates; 1 volume (Box 3)
    - Connecticut Highway Department: A report on the organization and procedures of the department, 1931 May; Griffenhagen and Associates; 1 volume (Box 3)
    - Standard Practice Instructions, Bulletin No. 1, Employment and compensation of the staff of the Bureau of Business Administration, 1931 May; Griffenhagen and Associates; 1 volume (Box 3)
    - Manual of rules and procedure for central filing, 1932; Griffenhagen and Associates; 1 volume (Box 3)
    - Manuals of rules of procedure for financial administration, 1932; Griffenhagen and Associates; 1 volume (Box 3)
    - History of road making in Connecticut, circa 1935; 1 volume (Box 3)
    - Merit system rules. State Personnel Department, 1942; 1 volume (Box 3a)
    - Land, building and equipment requirements, Bureau of Roadway Maintenance, 1944; 1 volume (Box 3a)
    - Job descriptions, State Highway Department, 1946; 1 volume (Box 3a)
    - Long range program, 1954 September-Octo9ber; 4 volumes (Box 3a)
    - Current maintenance matters, studied as of March 1, 1956, 1 volume (Box 3a)
    - Manual. Bureau of Property Control, 1956; 1 volume (Box 3a)
      Includes a memo regarding supervision of Portland Plant.
    - Master transportation study, 1970; Creator: Charles A. Maguire & Assoc., Inc.; 1 volume (Box 3a)
    - Introduction to UNIVAC "120" computer, 1958; 3 volumes (Box 3a)
      Includes photos and manuals.
  - 1993-042
    - State-wide highway planning survey in cooperation with United States Bureau of Public Roads, 1938; 1 folder (Box Shared box)
      Includes correspondence between R.L. Steiner and Charles Andrews on Colonial Connecticut schools, 1925.
  - 1993-046
    - Manual of procedure for the coding, extension, and punching operations in connection with the road use study, 1931 May 1; typescript, 1 folder (Box Shared box)
  - 2013-032
    - Code of Recommended Practice for Standards of Accuracy of Maps, 1945 January; 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Universal Mapping Committee - Large Scale Map Standards, 1979; 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Interchange Number: List of bridges and highways by town, 1987; 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Manual of Standard Procedures for Preparing State and County Maps, 1937-1965; 1 binder (Box 1)
    - Specifications for general highway and traffic maps, Bureau of Highway Planning, 1946-1953; 1 binder (Box 1)
    - Standard Specs. Aerial Topographic Map Preparation History, 1950-1955; 1 binder (Box 1)
    - State-wide highway planning survey in cooperation with United States Bureau of Public Roads, manual of instructions for rural road inventory, 1950-1955; 1 binder (Box 1)
- Series 4. Hartford Bridge Commission, 1939-1951
  - T002753
    - Minutes, 1939-1951
      - 1939 August 22 - 1941 March 17, 1 volume (Volume Item 4a)
      - 1941 April 14 - 1943 August 9, 1 volume (Volume Item 4b)
      - 1943 September 13 - 1950 April 17, 1 volume (Volume Item 4c)
      - 1950 June 27 - 1951 January 3, 1 volume (Volume Item 4d)
      - Charter Oak Bridge Scrapbook, 1939-1945; 1 volume (Volume Item 4e)
  - 1989-038
    - Construction records, 1940-1945 (Box 1)
      Construction records for the Charter Oak, Connecticut River and other small bridges.
      - Contracts and special provisions for construction, 1940-1945, bulk 1941-1942 (Box 1)
      - Bid summaries, 1941-1943 (Box 1)
      - Legislation, undated (Box 1)
      - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Surety bonds, 1940 (Box 1)
      - Project estimates and design reports, 1940-1945 (Box 1)
    - Estimates of expenditure requirements, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
      Includes: For the biennium ending June 30, 1951; For the Biennium ending June 30, 1953
    - Manager's daily reports for the Charter Oak Bridge, 1943-1950
      Statistics on revenue traffic, non-revenue traffic, and cash receipts.
      - 1943 September - 1947 (Box 2)
      - 1948 - 1950 February (Box 3)
  - 1999-092
    - Charter Oak Bridge Scrapbook supplement, 1945-1947; 1 folder (Volume Item 1)
- Series 5. Groton-New London Bridge Commission, 1939-1943
  - T002753
    - Minutes, 1939 July - 1943 June; 1 volume (Box Item 5)
  - 1999-090
    - Groton-New London Bridge Commission scrapbook, 1939-9143 (Box Box 1)
- Series 6. Old Lyme-Old Saybrook Bridge Commission, 1945-1951; T002753
  - Minutes, 1945-1951
    - 1945 August 22 - 1946 July 12, 1 volume (Volume Item 6a)
    - 1946 August 29 - 1947 December 3, 1 volume (Volume Item 6b)
    - 1948 January 6 - 1949 August 5, 1 volume (Volume Item 6c)
    - 1949 August 26 - 1951 January 2, 1 volume (Volume Item 6d)
    - 1945 August 17 - 1951 January 2, 1 volume (Volume Item 6e)
      Partial duplicate of Item 6d.
- Series 7. Reports and studies, 1939-1992, undated
  - T002753
    - Resolution authorizing construction of highway bridge between Hartford and East Hartford, 1940 (Box 7)
    - Project proposals, WPA trolley rail removal, 1942 (Box 7)
    - Hartford parking plaza, 1945 (Box 7)
    - Report on the proposed alternate route for the Wilbur Cross Parkway, 1942; Creator: New Haven City Plan Department (Box 7)
    - Report of the West Rock Tunnel, 1953 (Box 7)
    - Alternate location study for the relocation of Route U.S. 1 in the Stratford-Milford area, 1952 (Box 7)
    - Intersection of Church Street extensions and relocated Route 34 and Greenwich-Killingly expressway, 1955 (Box 7)
    - A highway lighting test installation, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Report to the Board of Selectmen from Town Plan Commission, Greenwich, on alternate route for the Post Road, 1951 (Box 7)
    - Preliminary report on buildings displaced by the alternate route, East-West Expressway, City of Hartford, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Planning report, Interstate 91, New Haven through Meriden, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Projects [for highway work] scheduled to be advertised, 1962-1963; 3 photostats (Box 7)
  - 1993-034
    - Statewide highway planning survey route mileage logs, undated; 1 volume (Box Shared box)
  - 2013-032
    - Connecticut Geographic Names Alphabetical Finding List, 1981; 1 volume (Box 1)
      Prepared from a computer file by the United States Department of Interior, Geological Survey, Branch of Geographic Names, Geographic Names Information System.
    - Delaware Mapping: A report describing the mapping procedures used by the Delaware Department of Highways and Transportation. Prepared by the State of Delaware Department of Highways and Transportation Mapping Section, in cooperation with the U.S. Department of Transportation Federal Highway Administration, undated; 1 volume (Box 1)
    - F.A. Charts Project Studies, 1940-1960; 1 binder (Box 1)
    - Official Mileage, Public Utilities Commission, State of Connecticut, 1939; 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Official Mileage, Public Utilities Commission, State of Connecticut, 1992; 1 volume (Box 1)
- Series 8. News clippings and maps, circa 1940-1965
  - Scrapbook, circa 1940-1960 (Box 8)
    Miscellaneous clippings and other items evidently removed from reports or scrapbooks.
- Series 9. Photographs, circa 1930-1958
  - T002753
    - Charter Oak Bridge, 1 album (Volume Item 9)
    - Raymond E. Baldwin Bridge
      - Volume 1, 1946-1947, undated; 1 album (Volume Item 10)
      - Volume 2, 1948, undated; 1 album (Volume Item 11)
      - Volume 3, undated; 1 album (Volume Item 12)
    - Thames River Bridge
      - 1941 February 20 - 1942 March 21, 1 album (Volume Item 13)
      - 1941 May 27 - 1943 March, 1 album (Volume Item 14)
      - 1941 February 20 - 1944 March 23, 1 album (Volume Item 15)
      - 1941 November 22 - 1943 September 10, 1 album (Volume Item 16)
    - Connecticut Turnpike
      - Volume 1, 1955 February - 1956 September; 1 album (Volume Item 17)
      - Volume 2, 1956 October - 1957 June; 1 album (Volume Item 18)
      - Volume 3, 1957 July 7 - 1958 January; 1 album (Volume Item 19)
      - Supplement, 1 album (Volume Item 20)
    - Road maintenance, 1940-1950; 1 album (Volume Item 21)
      Contents: Route 2, Colchester, mixed in place surfacing, drainage installation, Barber-Greene mixing plant; Route 2, Lebanon, plant mix; Route 4, Farmington, stone surface treatment; Route 167 Simsbury, stone surface treatment; Route 181, Barkhamsted, stone surface treatment; Route 72, Plainville, stone surface treatment and loading and spraying at quarry; Miscellaneous stone surface treatment; Portland, Route 14, mud jacking; Norfolk, Route 49, Butler's Bridge; Preston Route 2, PCS, North Stonington, Route 95, PCS; East Haddam, Route 149, PCS; Enfield, Route 20, PCS; Manchester, Route 44; Bethany, Route 69, PCS; New Hartford, Route 4, PCS; Wallingford, U.S. Route 5; North Haven and Wallingford, U.S. Route 5; Manchester, Road 437 at Hockanum River Bridge; Greenwich, U.S. Route 1; Eastford, Route 91; Hartford Expressway.
    - Road maintenance, 1930-1933, 1940-1946; 1 album (Volume Item 22)
      Contents: Derby, Route 34, retaining wall; Canton, Route 44, wire rope fence; New Hartford, Route 4, wire rope fence; Barkhamsted, Route 81, wire rope fence; Farmington, Route 4, wire rope fence; Avon, Route 167, wire rope fence; Bloomfield, Route 185, wire rope fence; Stone fence, unidentified; Waterford, Route 32, old and new location; Woodbridge, Route 67, site of accident; Bolton, Route 44, Reservoir dam failure; State Highway Dept. exhibit at Hartford State Armory; Suffield, Route 75, detour sign; New Milford, U.S. Route 7; Naugatuck, Route 8; Hartford-East Hartford, Charter Oak Bridge; East Haven, Route 142, retaining wall and steps; Middletown, Route 157; Goshen, Routes 123 and 61; Goshen-Cornwall town line, Bunker Hill picnic area; Goshen, Route 4; Glastonbury, Road 917; East Hartford, Charter Oak toll station; Various structures; Greenwich, Merritt Parkway toll station.
    - Road maintenance, circa 1941-1949; 1 album (Volume Item 23)
      Contents: Working on Merritt Parkway in Stamford; maintenance equipment; maintenance plant; snow equipment; snow conditions and removal.
    - Unidentified bridge construction, 1932 November 30 - 1933 May 15; 1 album (Volume Item 24)
    - Unidentified bridge construction, circa 1930-1939; 1 album (Volume Item 25)
    - Pavements and attractive nuisance, 1950; 1 album (Box Item 26)
      Contents: 1) Damage to pavement caused by trucks: Norwalk, Milford and West Haven, U.S. Route 1; Meriden and Wethersfield, Route 15 (Berlin Turnpike); Old Saybrook, Route 154; Avon and Canton, Route 44; Berlin and Wethersfield, Route 5/15 (Berlin Turnpike); Wethersfield and New Britain, Route 9; Guilford and Branford, U.S. Route 1; Torrington, Route 25. 2) Attractive nuisance: Protective fence at two wing walls of the bridge on Route 109 over Bantam River, Bantam, Conn.
      Also contains loose photos: Snow removal on Route 4, Goshen, 1940 February; Mianus River Bridge Construction, 1957 April 30; maintenance equipment.
    - James Henry MacDonald memorial dedication, 1933 August 30; 1 album (Volume Item 27)
      MacDonald was Connecticut Highway Commissioner from 1895 to 1913.
      The memorial is on Avon Mountain.
    - Bureau of Planning Studies planning survey, circa 1938-1939; 1 album (Volume Item 28)
      Includes a photograph with Warren M. Creamer, State Manager of the State-wide Highway Planning Survey. Also shows equipment used to conduct various measurements.
    - Bureau of Roadside Development, 1935-1936; 1 bundle (54 photographs) (Box Item 28a)
      Contents: Bolton, U.S. Routes 44 and 6A; Chaplin, Route 91; Columbia, Route 14; Danbury, U.S. Route 6; Farmington, U.S. Route 6A; Groton, Route 84; Haddam, Route 9; Meriden, Route 71; Newtown, Route 25; Prospect, Route 69; Stamford, Route 104; Stonington, Route 84; Trumbull, Route 25; Waterbury, Route 69; Wolcott, Route 69; Unidentified.
    - Bureau of Roadside Development, 1935; 1 envelope (Box Item 28b)
      Contents: Danbury, U.S. Route 6; Easton, Route 58; Stamford, Route 104; Stamford, Route 137; Cromwell, Route 9; Haddam, Route 9; North Stonington, Route 84; Branford, U.S. Route 1A; Shelton, Route 110; Trumbull, Route 25; Prospect, Route 69; Waterbury, Route 8; Winchester, Route 49; Norfolk, Route 49; Sharon, Route 4; Columbia, Route 14; Suffield, U.S. Route 5A; Windsor, U.S. Route 5A; Meriden, Route 71; Berlin, Route 71; Haddam, Route 9; Chaplin, Route 91; Loose material.
      Photographs are in folders with descriptions of projects.
    - Hartford-New London Road, Routes 2 and 85 from Glastonbury to New London, Proposed maintenance betterments, 1947 September; Creator: H.C. Casten; 1 bundle (Box Item 28c)
      Maps with photographs.
  - T003272
    - Merritt Parkway, 2 boxes (Box 1-2)
      Unprocessed
  - T003273
    - Unprocessed photographs, 8 boxes (Box A-H)
  - 1984-109
    - Unprocessed photographs, 2 boxes (Box 1-2)
      Prints and negatives.
- Series 12. State Highway Commissioner certificates of finished projects, 1895-1931; 1984-112
  Contains handwritten and typed certificates submitted for approval for road, trunk line, and finished wood guard railing projects. Certificates generally contain information about the project, materials purchased and cost claimed. Later certificates contain a more complete itemized listing of materials purchased by the town, including a final quantity estimate, contract price and the amount spent. Certificates sometimes also contained detailed descriptions regarding the road's physical dimensions. Some files include blueprints, sketches, daily labor cost reports, materials receipts, estimates of project cost sharing between the towns and the state, and the Comptroller's voucher receipt.
  - Andover - Bristol (Box 1)
  - Brookfield - Darien (Box 1)
  - Derby - Ellington (Box 3)
  - Enfield - Guilford (Box 4)
  - Haddam - Manchester (Box 5)
  - Mansfield - New Canaan (Box 6)
  - New Fairfield - North Canaan (Box 7)
  - North Haven - Preston (Box 8)
  - Prospect - Southbury (Box 9)
  - Southington - Torrington (Box 10)
  - Trumbull - Westport (Box 11)
  - Wethersfield - Woodstock (Box 12)
- Series 13. Merritt Parkway, 1937; T002753
  - Report, 1937; 1 volume (Box Item 29)
    Report by Public Works Commissioner Robert A. Hurley analyzing Highway Department projects especially the Merritt Parkway. Hurley makes suggested changes in the department's organization and operations.
    Includes photographs, graphs and charts.
- Series 14. West Rock Tunnel, 1948-1949; T002753
  - The West Rock Tunnel on the Wilbur Cross Parkway, 1948-1949, 1950; Creator: Connecticut State Highway Dept.; 1 volume, typescript (Box Item 30)
    Report with official construction photographs documenting construction of the West Rock Tunnel on the Wilbur Cross Parkway.
- Series 17. George S. Koch, 1975; T002753
  - A collection of addresses, talks and random thoughts by George S. Koch over the period 1955-1975, 1975 March; 1 volume (Box Item 31)
    Includes photographs.
- Series 19. Merritt Parkway Toll Plazas, 1939-1988
  - Photographs
    - Greenwich Toll Plaza, 1988; 15 photographs (1 folder), b&w, 8.5 x 11 in.; 1988-009; Historic Resources Survey
      - Office, View west
      - Inside office, Lunch area
      - Inside toll house control office
      - Toll house, View north-northeast
      - Toll house and office, South face, View west
      - View South-Southwest, North face, Heading toward New York
      - South face, View North-Northeast
      - Automatic toll machine, View South-Southwest
      - Automatic toll house timbers, underside of roof
      - Underside roof and timbers
      - Inside toll house
      - Inside toll house
      - Automatic toll machine collector and counter
      - Toll house, View west
      - Toll house and office, South face, View North-Northeast
    - Milford Toll Plaza, 1988; 12 photographs (1 folder), b&w, 8.5 x 11 in.; 1988-034; Historic Resources Survey
      - View north east showing west side of plaza
      - View south east showing plaza office
      - View north showing toll booths for the I-95 connector
      - View south east showing toll booths, timber beam roof
      - View south showing east side of plaza and north side of plaza office
      - View north east showing interior, cash box, intercom in toll booth for the I-95 connector
      - Interior view in rear of plaza office showing heating system
      - View north east showing toll booths, toll signs, roof and traffic control lights
      - View north showing timber roof framing
      - Interior view
      - Interior view of plaza office showing loose change counter, computer and desks
      - Interior view of plaza office showing change counters for tolls and desk
  - Blueprints, T003274
    - Toll station, Greenwich, Conn., Sewage disposal system, 1940 September 19; 1 sheet
    - Parkway toll station for State Highway Dept., 1940 March 18; 4 sheets
      Includes: No. 3, Elevations & sections of toll house, 2 copies; No. 4, Plans & elevations, Administration building; No. 5, Plan, Typical toll booth
    - Parkway toll station & administration building for State Highway Dept., 1940 March 8; 3 sheets
      Includes: No. E-1, Electrical plan & details, Merrit Parkway, Creenwich, CT; No. E-1, Electrical plan & details, Wilbur Cross Parkway. Milford, Conn.; No. E-2, Electrical plan and elev, Merrit Parkway, Greenwich, CT
    - Plumbing & heating ,Administration and toll buildings, Merritt Parkway, 1939 December 29; 1 sheet
- Series 21. Surveyor field books, 1956-1962; 1989-004
  Notes regarding various State Highway Department projects from across the state.
  - Aerial map checks (Box 1)
    - Avon to Windsor, 1958 July; No. A (Box 1)
    - Bloomfield - East Granby - Simsbury; Crowell - Berlin; Bloomfield - West Hartford, 1957; No. A (Box 1)
    - East Hartford Center, 1961 May; No. A (Box 1)
    - East Hartford - Berlin, 1956 March; No. A (Box 1)
    - East Hartford - South Windsor, 1961 March - April; No. B (Box 1)
    - Elmwood, 1961 April; No. C (Box 1)
    - Glastonbury, 1956 February; 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - Glastonbury, 1956 May; 2 volumes, No. 53-84, A, B (Box 1)
    - Glastonbury to Manchester, 1958 May; No. A (Box 1)
    - Hartford - Bloomfield, Relocation Route 9, undated; No. A (Box 1)
    - Hartford - Bloomfield -Enfield - Suffield, 1957; No. B (Box 1)
    - Manchester to Vernon, 1958 March; No. A (Box 1)
    - Middletown to Southington, Rt. 6A, undated; No. A (Box 1)
    - New Britain, 1962 April; 1 of 1 (Box 1)
    - New Britain, 1961 May; No. E, Sheet 1 of 1 (Box 1)
    - New Britain to Hartford, 1961 May; No. G, Sheet 2 of 6 (Box 1)
    - New Britain to Hartford, 1961 April; No. I, Sheet 4 of 6 (Box 1)
    - Plainville to West Hartford, Relocation Route 6, 1957 March; No. A (Box 1)
    - Plainville to Plymouth, Relocation Route 72, 1959 August; 2 volumes, No. A & B (Box 1)
    - Plainville to Simsbury, 1959 June - July; 3 volumes, No. A, B, and unnumbered (Box 2)
    - Wethersfield, Berlin Turnpike, 1961 April; No. D (Box 2)
  - Avon - West Hartford, Avon Mt. - Creeper Lane, undated; 5 volumes, No. 04-55, A, B, C, D, E (Box 2)
  - Bloomfield, Maple Ave., undated; 4 volumes, No. 11-97, A, B, C, D (Box 2)
  - Bulkeley Bridge, undated; No. A (Box 2)
  - Cromwell, Relocation Route 9, 1951 July; No. 33-60, A (Box 2)
  - Cromwell, Relocation Route 9, 1954 February - March; 2 volumes, No. 33-60, A, B (Box 2)
  - East Hartford, Connecticut Blvd., undated (Box 2)
  - East Hartford, Garage storage area, undated (Box 2)
  - Mountain Road drainage, undated; 2 volumes, No. 64-66 (Box 2)
  - Manchester, Channelization, undated; 3 volumes, No. 76-72 (Box 2)
    No. 1: Line notes; No. 4-5: X-section
  - Mansfield, Route 32, 1956 June; 2 volumes, No. 77-88 (Box 3)
  - Middletown, Newfield Street, undated; 5 volumes, No. 82-64, A, B, C, D, E (Box 3)
  - Middletown, Route 9, undated; No. 82-86 (Box 3)
  - New Hartford - Canton, Relocation Route 4, undated; 2 volumes, No. 657, 658 (Box 3)